if you keep looking in the kitchen at
your husband the way you've been looking
at your husband in the kitchen then you
will never see Nirvana then he goes to
the next chapter
what's the next chapter investigate
desire investigate desire okay I think
when you teach it it's very very
important to say it's not wrong to want
things okay that's a big stupid low
tongue ALPA booty idea okay smile like
Minnie Minnie brain I loved that
maybe I'll call my band the mini brains
I keep looking for a new name of course
I have to have a band to name it but
that's a little detail okay he's gonna
investigate desire is it wrong to want
things not at all I mean we want to
escape pain this morning we did 13-step
you got that Tim you want to put it up
we did a 13 step meditation by there it
is if you want to if you want to slowly
or Tim can send it out I know you could
take it with your phone how's that then
I don't have to interrupt the class
that's the meditation we we work this
much how'd it feel
I liked it yeah we're doing all this
emptiness meditation we're not doing
much sweetiepie meditation I like this
one those are the classic steps okay it
mixes that it mixes three things for $30
it makes it raise your hand no money no
hand no money honey yeah she didn't do
one yet okay go ahead
don't don't men and seven steps to
achieve what it is that mama mama
meditation exchanging suffer notice
three greatest meditations in one that
must be from
booty's what's that big mind people yeah
those are mercedes-benz people mental
mercedes-benz people then makes these
three kinds of love three kinds of love
meditation mixed together it's it should
maybe you know try this car for a few
weeks you know do your lions dance do
your afternoon Tong men and then try
this car out try this new car okay test
drive it for me
tell me what you think okay when I see
you in Bali we have some more space
Jasmine where are you yeah just for
people from Diamond Mountain group and
their friends and everybody else there's
25 places left okay she can squeeze you
in
okay you can sleep on the beach okay
tell me how it went okay when we get to
Bali that's in December right so tell me
how how did this new car feel how's this
new car feel okay you're the first
people to try this new car I guess that
you can call this a secret meditation
that the dialogues teacher is to do okay
so that's pretty chill pretty cool
pretty sick in surfing now this if you
had a really good way they say man that
was a sick way you think this that's a
real sick meditation we tried that okay
so we're gonna go on to desire I think
it's kind of nice that we are leaving
the Alpha Buddhist okay we're leaving
the accounts and by the way we're
supposed to cover six chapters in this
course on money pinch Allah Almighty
permission I don't know if we're gonna
make it but I'm trying okay I'm really
trying okay so here we go we're moving
on to desire and
and here's the structure okay mm-hmm by
the way we're gonna take a break
Tina in 11 minutes I told you somebody
asked me how many students you want in
your life Kesha 365 with different
birthdays then I can get per taking
every day so maybe there's a birthday
today
alright so according to Tony Tony Lama
is struggling like everybody else for
the last 2,000 years they're struggling
to understand the structure of the 27
chapters okay it looks like the
gardener's just hey check this out
alright check this out check this out
and and it's difficult to see any real
pattern okay it's difficult to see he's
going there's logic to he throws out
different subjects so one of the most
one of the greatest things Johnny lama
has done is to try to put it into a
structure he says look it's logical you
just can't see it I'll help you okay and
he gives us a structure okay so here he
goes NEPA me patelliday up a tube check
a Palazzo okay
duty means proof taesoo means those
three what three yeah
the subject alone three last chapters
which is basically poon say poon come KJ
soon I'll be Dharma first chapter the
most famous first chapter in history of
Buddhism okay
parts of you punk
come the 18 categories are the five
elements KJ the 12 sense Paris and their
objects he said look we finished us now
he says let's go on to arguments people
make you know people try to give
arguments of why those three should come
from their own side okay now maybe you
noticed each one of the chapters already
started with somebody making an argument
okay you know oh the eyes should be
connected to the blue there should be a
nature of the eye to the blue because
Buddha taught it okay or there should be
there should be a connection between the
chemicals in your body in the body that
they produce if there's no connection
how can you be walking around okay got
it
what was the third one sky oh yeah if it
has a definition and you're gonna define
it duh there's a connection you know you
don't use first definition to fits empty
space there must be some connection okay
that's the guy the other guy okay now
the other guy's gonna say I have new
arguments for you why why the husband
come from his own side I have new new
arguments and he's gonna give three okay
first he's gonna talk about negative
emotions there is some stuff nature
Ockman in negative emotions okay oh by
the way before I forget there's one word
you need to finish your homework
your last homework it's another Sanskrit
word okay let me find it for you
[Music]
hmm okay on homework number four there
are three sanskrit words if you don't
know them you can't finish your homework
one of them we finish this definition
what's the Sanskrit lacuna which also
means the sign that's glued to the thing
which indicates this is fire hot and
burns you okay if you get those two
signs then that's fire okay if it's hot
and if it burns you when you touch it
okay that's the luck you know that it's
a fire okay
it's kind of like the signs that belong
to that thing okay got it
okay that's luck Sina we finished that
what's the English word reach that but
that worm that connect to your skin eat
your skin cannot dissipate huh huh
yeah glue you can say also okay so
connected to that thing by nature nobody
made fire hot yeah and you made fire hot
you made fire okay got it you made
husband stupid okay don't blame the
husband okay just kidding
say Akasha space empty space did I give
you the sense I'll just repeat it it
means space or empty space Akasha and it
comes from a root cus ka s the rudest
cuss ka s and it means to open but in a
sense to cut open okay like you cut
something and you open it and you see
what's inside okay Akasha Akasha means
very open that means very it's not the
negative okay
Akasha very much very open and English
words are cast which means a society
group they cut into different groups or
castrate which means to cut the male
organ from the cow okay or chest which
means cut off from bad qualities it
means a very good person okay
okay they all come from cussed cuss but
the one I'm really interested in and the
one I didn't teach you yet that you need
to do homework for is portable say para
what about means before came before puta
same in Indonesia Pasha
yeah Oh
port of a colour so a lot of their
language a lot of pasa language from
Indonesia comes from this okay put about
means before it comes from a root part
which means to pass to pass okay
and the English cognates are before and
forward / became for okay forward okay
[Music]
$50 it's okay I have to ask we get
married
I gotta get used to it why is why is
port of an important in this last
chapter what was the last chapter bone
no that's the next chapter six and five
what's chapter 5 about space yeah which
came first the definition oh I just gave
you the answer okay
a lot of these new gardener arguments
are based on which is portable which is
Puma okay so the word it's a small word
it's not a very important word you know
you don't spend two hours talking about
before but in this book you do you have
to talk about before okay
which came first the elements are the
products of the elements which came
first your eye or the blue Cup which
came first which came first which came
first the husband
yelling husband or the wife what's the
wrong human computer what's wrong look
mean yeah you get hungry in these books
for just tell me what's right in the
gardener you know stop all these
arguments you know I understand you like
to argue I understand you like the front
we read the whole book we listened to it
for day after day after day now can you
just tell us what's correct what's your
system okay what is our system which
came first the cup or the eye or the I
see the cup which came from neither one
their balls coming at the same time it's
the wrong okay they are growing from
sharing your coffee with other people
last week okay
Geshe Michaels tongue patch taste patch
yeah yeah and the coffee are coming from
the same cause which is kindness to
other people which is kindness to other
people if your emptiness discussion
doesn't reach kindness you don't
understand emptiness okay if your
emptiness bla bla bla bla bla and you
don't use it as a reason to take care of
other people then you you know you have
failed you failed as a Buddhist okay and
if you're kind without understanding why
you also failed as a Buddhist
okay if you're kind but you don't know
why you also fail as a Buddhist okay got
it
okay cuz it won't last
it will break you know I mean there's
only a little bit of cake and only one
person can get it it will fail okay
thank you for the coffee
hey Maria how are you what's that alarm
wait that's a birthday alarm
[Music]
[Applause]
okay it's not Alice sister it's her
mother you are going to have cake we can
see that when the cow pie is actually
coming out of the cow vodka vodka
McCarroll then for a short time the cow
pies bottom becomes its top do you
follow me
goats up Jane nods concentrating
fiercely but then she says when it
topples over and plops on the grass the
top as it were changes into the bottom
do you see okay wait wait this needs a
commentary okay okay just short
commentary okay so some cobbler had a
very famous student named Gil top gene
but he was famous before he meant from
copper and he was the greatest logician
intimate and very very famous and a
little bit proud to tell you the truth
and he heard some copper some coppers
start to get very popular it's like me
and art okay
and so coppers start to get very popular
as a teacher so Celtic J's make a plan I
will go to his teaching and I will
disrupt it I will mess up the teaching
which is very bad karma
and so he's a little bit late to get to
the teaching so he decided to take a
shortcut which are not gonna do it time
among he decided not to keep the
building inside he cut short cut then he
got lost
okay and he's late so then he saw he got
lost he saw a girl herding cows
okay cowherd girl dirty poor uneducated
and he said you know do you know where's
big nose giving the teaching today
so the tsongkhapa's people who didn't
like to copper call him mr. big nose not
with Jimbo this means hey do you know
what big nose is giving the teaching
today and the girls like big nose I
don't know any big nose and who's asking
he's his arm kill today and she's like
wow you a girl today
yeah you're the great logician yeah
that's me yeah I'm famous everywhere
even the cowgirls know me
and then she said oh I always had a
logic question in my mind and he's like
go ahead
I I have time I'm not in a big rush and
she said you know all day long I'm
taking care of these cows and sometimes
they make a poopoo and when they make a
poopoo that the tail comes up if you
watch a cow make a poopoo then the butt
comes up and the poop comes up and then
the poop comes down so when the poo
first come out this is the bottom but
when it can fall down the bottom becomes
the top so logically what's the top of
the poop and what's the bottom of the
truth
then bounce MJ's like yeah I don't know
I don't know then the girl said oh okay
uh-oh and the guy you're looking for the
unmatched the greatest Lama fantastic
beautiful man greatest heart Savior of
Tibet is that what you're looking for
when you say big nose then suddenly she
has incense in her hand like that I
bowed to toccata
instead start burning oh and then she
said did she change into Roger Guinea
did she say if you wanna go to his
teaching that way go that way okay then
he's like wow you want the rest three so
that's the poop okay then but on the way
he'd forget about veggie Guinea and he
has a big big in llama her you know
and he designed he will walk into the
teaching with the llama head which is
very disrespectful it's like you should
take off your cowboy hat so he wear his
hat he go to the temple where it some
cop was teaching and one of some couples
teaching no one tapa teacher-student
known tapa Sacco humble who is that
yeah the one who who got the three
principal paths letter he can read
people's mind and he said guilt objec
Amin he said he's not gonna take his hat
off and he climb up on the roof very
fast and he'd get a long string and a
hook and just when girls object come in
the door he hooked that hat and the hat
come off on gelt of his hand and
everybody look at the door he said Wow
even Cal today take his hat off
this song kappa must be amazing person
then just adjacent then he said i will
go up and sit with tsongkhapa on the
throne which is completely against every
Buddhist role so he go up and sit with
the Lama and so God was like hi and so
copper keep teaching you know about
logic actually and then counts up just
like I don't know this is pretty good
stuff I think I should get down there
so he moved down there you know and then
some copper keep teaching teaching
teaching in Celtic Jay said oh my god
this guy he's beyond beyond beyond and
he bowed down to some copper and he said
please let me stay with you my whole
life I don't want to leave you my whole
life so that's a poop story
[Applause]
you need a break you need let's take a
little break okay we'll take a little
break so you got put about right before
and you know why it's important which
came first the chicken or the egg
same question okay take a break one more
small part yeah so you have put about
and now you can do that homework now
we're gonna talk about so we're going to
talk about desire and the thing that you
want and let's say I have desire for
alcohol okay both of my parents were
alcoholic so I grew up with the
alcoholics you know and I you know was
everywhere in the house and it caused a
lot of problems and so I used to wonder
yeah you know when your parents are
alcoholic you like wow that must be
really good and then when they go out
one day you try to drink the stuff and
you're like ah what's wrong with this
guy what am i drinking that stuff and it
tastes terrible right so in the sixth
chapter we're gonna investigate where is
the pleasure in the alcohol okay where
is the pleasure in the alcohol so many
people are addicted to alcohol or it
could be chocolate or other things okay
but where where is the pleasure like in
the aspirin where is the chemical that
takes away your pain okay and in the
alcohol where is the stuff
that makes you feel more relaxed if you
drink wine where is it in the wine okay
and then when you're when the wine
touches your tongue then how does it
happen that you feel more relaxed
okay what is in the wine that makes you
more relaxed so we have to talk about it
okay we're gonna talk about desire and
it's like talking about the aspirin
there's something in the wine that makes
you relax or you believe that and how
does the wine touch your tongue and how
does it affect your mind okay and then
how do people start to get addiction
okay how does that happen and it's very
important for all of us because
according to Buddhism we're all addicted
to something okay and some addictions
are legal you know like in the US now
many states made it legal to use
marijuana it used to be only go
no it's illegal so some addictions are
legal okay that you don't go to jail in
in many places in America now if you
smoking marijuana which is really bad
idea by the way it makes you really
stupid if you want to get more stupid
smoked marijuana
easy method then some addictions are
illegal right like cocaine or heroin
some are illegal and some addictions are
approved by society like if people over
work too hard people praise them oh you
are hard-working you know they ignore
their kids they ignore their family they
ignore their parents they go higher
higher position in the company they
never go home
it hurts a lot of people but but society
says oh this is a good addiction we like
this addiction you are a real what do
you call it big executive you know
you're a hard hard pushing executive
it's amazing you can do so much okay so
some addictions are approved some
addictions are you have to keep quiet
right some addictions you have to hide
so addictions are a big question how
does desire work how do you get what you
want out of your addiction if you're
addicted to a lot of people in America
are addicted to sugar sweet things and
so when your tongue touches the churro
and you get that first sweet taste from
the children right so what's happening
how is it possible okay how are the
little pieces of sugar touching your
tongue how is the pleasure going from
the churro to your tongue and we have to
think about it we have to find the
answer okay and this is a whole level
what level in this year novel six about
addiction and I'm gonna tell you where
we want to go and then we'll then where
we're finished today we finish we can
continue tomorrow but I'll tell you
where I want to go with addiction okay
this is chapter six this is where I want
to go the reason my parents drank
alcohol and died they both died from
alcohol they wanted happiness they
wanted pleasure you know many many
people drink wine at dinner time they
say it makes me more relaxed okay so we
believe or we feel strongly that there's
a some relaxation exist in the one
somehow the wine has
something inside which makes us relax we
believe that that's why you drink wine
before dinner that's why many people
drink wine before dinner in Sedona the
population mix is mostly hippies about
my age there are hippies who had some
money and went to Sedona because it's a
little bit you know spiritual place and
so wine is very popular there every
store sells many kinds of wine because
when you get to 50 60 years old your
body start to hurt different things
start to hurt every day there's a new
story and so people drink wine you know
at the store the grocery store has
thousand kinds of wine you know it's
supposed to sell bananas and I don't
know bread and there's half the stores
wine so it means the population in that
city they like to have a little wine
before they go to bed it helps them to
sleep it makes them more relaxed ok but
it has all these other problems ok
so we have to investigate right we're
gonna do an investigation of a wine how
does it work you know what does it do
for you and my goal ok my going this
class and I think the garden is gone
it's not that you shouldn't like things
that's a misunderstanding of Buddhism ok
you look at those paintings of Buddhist
heaven I meet the bus heaven not
everybody like this you know they're
having fun ok that but they don't have
desire you see they don't have wrong
desire ok so I think you have to divide
between good desire and that desire and
this is where we're going this is where
chapter 6 is going ok is it wrong to
want to be happy is it wrong to want to
relax before dinner or before you go to
bed is that a bad thing
are you a bad person if you buy wine
because you want to be relaxed you know
are you a bad person is it is it all
people who buy wine cannot be Buddhist
you're bad person okay is that the
meaning of desire
what does desire means so we're gonna
talk about desire and the goal okay
here's the goal is to get the feeling
that you get from the wine and you don't
even need the wine okay with you you
want we're gonna find we're gonna
investigate wine to find out how you can
get the pleasant feeling from wine
without the wine and it's much cheaper
okay alright understand that's what
we're going I'm not teaching you the
chapter about desire so that you can
become super boring person who never
laughs who never enjoy their food never
enjoy their life it's not my goal I'm
but up the goal is the opposite I want
you to enjoy everything okay what's the
secret to enjoy everything okay
all right cool that's where we're going
all right all right let's go back to mr.
Nagarjuna we are reaching chapter six
this is an investigation of desire and
attachment good
and I I started to teach you those words
now on the homework I think the last
part is the last part of the last
chapter and we had what was the last
idea in the last chapter huh put of us
pretty good
ALPA body please yeah
mini brains okay mini brains
ALPA body means people who have small
brain okay and the Guardian is a little
bit hot right he said oh hi mini brain
hi mini brain it's kind of insult right
hey mini brain how are you you know you
can't figure it out what 50 dollars
what what was in that verse don't look
what was in the verse
why why he called a mini brain wait say
gee are you raising your hand or you
there's a fly okay okay that's here nice
okay $25 each thinking that things exist
from their own side or that they don't
exist at all
$75 answer it's a $75 answer to a $50
question since that if you give a really
good answer it's like I don't know you
get a tip alright good answer yeah he
said if you think things have to exist
from their own side but if they don't
then they don't exist at all then you
lost the middle way and your upper body
you have a small mind okay you have this
moment that we finished the last chapter
okay now we go to investigation of
desire and attachment